Register to The E.Y. Harburg Collection
Yale University Music Library
The E.Y. Harburg Collection
1929-1968
MSS 83
Yale University Music Library
30
(26 boxes)
Writings and other papers by and about the American lyricist E.Y. ("Yip") Harburg
Harburg, E. Y. (Edgar Yipsel), 1896-1981
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The E.Y. Harburg Collection was established at Yale University by E. Y. Harburg in 1968.
Arrangement
In 2 series as follows: I. Writings. II. Harburgiana.
Scope and Contents
The E. Y. Harburg Collection documents Harburg's life and career as a lyricist for musicals, films, and popular songs chiefly through his writings. The Collection also contains correspondence, publicity, reviews, and memorabilia.
Biographical / Historical
Edgar Yipsel ("Yip") Harburg was born Irwin Hochberg on April 8, 1896, on the Lower East Side of Manhattan. (Some sources give the year of his birth as 1898.) He showed his flair for light verse at an early age, but after graduating from the City College of New York in 1917, he pursued a career in business, while continuing to write in his spare time. After a period of prosperity, his electrical supply company failed in the late 1920s, and he decided to change careers.
Harburg quickly achieved great success as a lyricist. Over the years, he collaborated with many composers, including Jay Gorney, Vernon Duke, Harold Arlen, Jerome Kern, Burton Lane, Sammy Fain, and Jule Styne. Harburg wrote the lyrics for shows such as Finian's Rainbow and films such as The Wizard of Oz. His long list of hit songs includes "Brother, Can You Spare a Dime?," "April in Paris," "It's Only a Paper Moon," "Over the Rainbow," and "How are Things in Glocca Morra?"
Harburg's Hollywood career came to a halt in the early 1950s when he was blacklisted. A staunch advocate of a variety of left-leaning causes, Harburg was never a member of the Communist Party. The blacklist did not prevent him from working on Broadway, but his musicals after Finian's Rainbow did not match the success of his earlier works.
Yip Harburg died on March 5, 1981 in Brentwood, California.
Blacklisting of entertainers -- United States; Musicals; Songs; Arlen, Harold, 1905-1986; Behrman, S. N. (Samuel Nathaniel), 1893-1973; Belafonte, Harry, 1927-; Berlin, Irving, 1888-1989; Buchwald, Art, 1925-; Crawford, Cheryl, 1902-1986; Dassin, Jules, 1911-2008; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955; Fosse, Bob, 1927-1987; Fulbright, J. William (James William), 1905-1995; Gershwin, Ira, 1896-1983; Guthrie, Tyrone, 1900-1971; Hammerstein, Oscar, II, 1895-1960; Harburg, E. Y. (Edgar Yipsel), 1896-1981; Hart, Moss, 1904-1961; Kaufman, George S. (George Simon), 1889-1961; Kay, Hershy, 1919-1981; Kazan, Elia, 1909-2003; Lahr, Bert, 1895-1967; Lane, Burton, 1912-1997; Lazar, Irving, 1907-1993; Lieberson, Goddard, 1911-1977; Lilienthal, David Eli, 1899-1981; Loesser, Frank, 1910-1969; Logan, Joshua, 1936-1987; Lomax, Alan, 1915-2002; Mercer, Johnny, 1909-1976; Minnelli, Vincente, 1903-1986; Morse, Wayne L. (Wayne Lyman), 1900-1974; O'Casey, Sean, 1880-1964; Perelman, S. J. (Sidney Joseph), 1904-1979; Poitier, Sidney, 1927-; Porter, Cole, 1891-1964; Prince, Harold, 1928-; Rice, Elmer, 1892-1967; Rodgers, Richard, 1902-1979; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Rose, Billy, 1899-1966; Seeger, Pete, 1919-2014; Sinatra, Frank, 1915-1998; Snow, Edgar, 1905-1972; Taylor, Deems, 1885-1966; Trumbo, Dalton, 1905-1976; Wallace, Mike, 1918-2012; Wilkins, Roy, 1901-1981; Wouk, Herman, 1915-
- Writings, 1929-1968; Series I; 20 boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains Harburg's writings for the American musical theatre and film, his light verse, songs written for political benefits, and various speeches, articles and testimonials.
  The musical productions are arranged in chronological order, and all lyrics, libretti, scores, and notes pertaining to a particular musical, whether authored by Harburg or not, are filed together. Songs used in a musical are arranged, when possible, in their order of appearance in the Broadway production (or motion picture). In cases where a musical took several years to develop and underwent several revisions--as did The Happiest Girl in the World and Darling of the Day, for example--the scripts and notes are arranged chronologically. The songs, however, are arranged in their order of appearance in the Broadway production, and any earlier versions of a song are filed with the final version.
  Unpublished individual songs, light verse, songs written for political benefits, and various speeches, articles, and testimonials are all arranged chronologically by category.
  - Writings: Lyrics, Libretti, and Scores
    - Eveready Hour radio scripts
      - Holograph description of "Eveready Hour" scripts, in red ink, 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - The Mayor of Hogan's Alley ("Eveready Hour," CBS radio, 1929 Feb 19) (Box 1, Folder 1)
        General
        Typed script of one-act musical play; music by Jay Gorney & Henry Souvaine [with script by E.Y. Harburg] -- 27 pages
      - How's the Judge[?] ("Eveready Hour," CBS radio, 1929 May 14) (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - For Dear Old Delta ("Eveready Hour," CBS radio [1929]) (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Typed script of one-act musical play; music by Jay Gorney & Henry Souvaine [with script by E.Y. Harburg] -- 29 pages
    - Early Lyrics, [1929-1930?]
      - Holograph description of lyrics, in pencil, 1 page (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Typed Lyrics (Box 1, Folder 2)
        "Oh My! What a Wonderful World!" [on verso of description] -- 1 page
        "Baby, Be Yourself" -- 1 page
        ["But Whom Do You Kiss Good Night?"] -- 1 page
        "Dawg Gone 'Em -- 2 pages
        "Gotta Passport to Paradise" -- 1 page
        "Heads Up" -- 1 page
        "If I Didn't Have You" -- 1 page
        "I'm Plenty That Way" -- 1 page
        "It Can't Be True" -- 1 page
        "Some Night When the Moon is Blue" [chorus only] -- 1 page
        "Three Flights Up" -- 1 page
        "Something Peculiar (Just Happened to Me)" -- 1 page
        "Where Are You?" -- 1 page
        "While We're Here" -- 1 page
        "The World Is In My Arms" [E.Y. Harburg note: "not the song by the same title in Hold On To Your Hats"] -- 1 page
        "You Started This" [chorus only] -- 1 page
        "Your Love is Music" -- 1 page
    - Early Lyrics, 1930
      - Holograph notes & lyrics, in ink (Box 1, Folder 3)
        "Darn You" [E.Y. Harburg note: tune by Dana Suesse] -- 1 page
        "Do I Need You?" (2nd chorus) -- 1 page
        "Hanging On to You" [E.Y. Harburg note: Souvaine-Harburg] -- 1 page
        ["I'm Not Myself When I'm Alone with You"] -- 1 page
        "Life Goes On" [E.Y. Harburg note: tune by Dana Seusse] -- 1 page
        "Save Your Tears" [E.Y. Harburg note: Oscar Levant tune] -- 1 page
        ["Those Lips, Those Eyes"] [E.Y. Harburg note: for Paramount Pictures] -- 1 page
        Notes: miscellaneous titles, lines, rhymes, etc. -- 22 pages
    - Early Lyrics, 1929-1933
      - Published piano-vocal scores with lyrics, leather-bound volume (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "What Wouldn't I Do For That Man" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Just a Melody for a Memory" (E.Y. Harburg-Irving Kahal-Gorney-Fain, 1929), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "It Can't Go On Like This" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
          Insert: holograph note, in pencil
        - "I Am Only Human After All" (E.Y. Harburg-Ira Gershwin-Vernon Duke), 5 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Careful with My Heart" (E.Y. Harburg-Senia Pokrass), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Suddenly" (E.Y. Harburg-Rose-Duke), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Moon About Town" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "I Like the Likes of You" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "New Deal Rhythm" (E.Y. Harburg-Roger Edens), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Let's Make Love Like the Crocodiles" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "There's a Little Bit of You (in Every Love Song)" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Ah, But Is It Love?" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Moonlight and Pretzels" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "It's Only a Paper Moon" (E.Y. Harburg-Arlen), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
          Insert: holograph note, in ink
        - "Losing You" (E.Y. Harburg-Pokrass), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Isn't It Heavenly" (E.Y. Harburg-Joseph Meyer), 5 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "April in Paris" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Off Again, On Again" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "So Nonchalant" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke), 5 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "That's Life" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke), 6 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "A Penny for Your Thoughts" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke), 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Speaking of Love" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Where Have We Met Before?" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Satan's Li'l Lamb" (E.Y. Harburg-Johnny Mercer-Arlen), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Whistling for a Kiss" (E.Y. Harburg-Mercer-Arlen), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Brother, Can You Spare a Dime?" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Riddle Me This" (E.Y. Harburg-Lewis Gensler), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Falling Off the Wagon" (E.Y. Harburg-Gensler), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "How Do You Do It?" (E.Y. Harburg-Gensler), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Thrill Me" (E.Y. Harburg-Gensler), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Love and Nuts and Noodles (Bring 'Em Back Alive)" (E.Y. Harburg-Gensler), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Your Are the First Love" (E.Y. Harburg-Emmerich Kalman), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Pretty Little Words" (E.Y. Harburg-Oscar Levant), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "My Fortune is Love" (E.Y. Harburg-Robert Stolz), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "I'll Make a Home for Your Love (in This Heart of Mine)" (E.Y. Harburg-Werner R. Heyman), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Muchacha" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney-Duke), 5 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Hot Moonlight" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Say It!" (E.Y. Harburg-Levant), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Five Minutes of Spring" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 5 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "You Started Something" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "My Little Prayer" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Applause and Glorifying the American Girl (Paramount Pictures musicals, both 1929)
      - "What Wouldn't I Do For That Man!" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney) (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Manuscript of piano-vocal score, handwritten in pencil [by Gorney or copyist?] -- 2 pages
        Insert: handwritten note from Jay Gorney -- 1 page
    - Battle of Paris (Paramount Pictures, 1929)
      - "Battle of Paris" [prologue to film], 1 page (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Typed lyrics with holograph annotation
    - The Vanderbilt Revue (N.Y. opening: Vanderbilt Theatre, 1930 Nov 10)
      - "Ex-Gigolo" (E.Y. Harburg-Mario Braggiotti), 1 page (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Holograph lyrics for second chorus, in ink
    - Leave It To Lester [film, 1930]
      - "I'm Yours" (E.Y. Harburg-Johnny Green; also used in The Stooge, 1952), 1 page (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Typed lyrics with holograph corrections
    - Accidentally Yours (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney songs; did not open in New York)
      - "Five Minutes of Spring", 1 page (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Holograph lyrics, draft in pencil
    - Ballyhoo of 1932 (N.Y. opening: 1932 Sep 6; E.Y. Harburg-Lewis Gensler songs)
      - Office of Ballyhoo (sketch), 1 page (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Holograph draft of patter, in pencil
      - "How Do You Do It?" and "I'm Off of You", 2 copies, 1 page each (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Typed lyrics
      - "Thrill Me", 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Holograph notes for lyrics, in pencil
      - "I'm a Man About Yonkers", 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Typed lyrics with holograph additions, in pencil
      - "I'm a Man About Yonkers", 1 page (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Holograph draft of verse, in pencil
      - "Ballyhujah", 2 copies, 2 pages each (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "Ballyhujah", 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "Ballyhooey Lassies" [Opening, Act III], 1 page each (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Typed lyrics, 3 copies
      - "Love and Nuts and Noodles", 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "What Have You Got to Have?", 1 page each (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "I'm Tired of Love", 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "I'm Tired of Love", 1 page (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "I Lerve You", 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Barn Dance, Act II, Scene 7, 1 page (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Holograph notes for patter, in pencil
      - "Baby, We're Through", 1 page (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "'Cause You Won't Do Right By Me" [not used; earlier version of "Buds Won't Bud"], 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Holograph lyrics, in pencil
      - "How About a Little Date for Breakfast?" [not used], 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "She'll Be Coming 'Round the Catskill Mountains" [not used] (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Typed lyrics, chorus only -- 1 page
        Holograph notes for lyrics, in pencil -- 2 pages
      - "As Long as We Have Bromo Seltzer in Our Love Nest" [not used] (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Typed Lyrics, 3 copies -- 1 page each
        Holograph notes for lyrics -- 3 pages
      - Miscellaneous holograph notes, in pencil, 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Americana (N.Y. opening: Sam. S. Shubert Theatre, 1932 Oct 31)
      - "Uncle Sam Needs a Man Who Can Take It" (E.Y. Harburg-?), 1 page (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Holograph notes for lyrics
      - "Brother, Can You Spare a Dime?" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 1 page (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - "Brother, Can You Spare a Dime?" [by Gorney or copyist?] (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Manuscript of piano-vocal score with lyrics handwritten -- 4 pages
        Holograph notes for lyrics, in pencil -- 6 pages
      - "Let Me Match My Private Life with Yours" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke), 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - "Five Minutes of Spring" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 1 page (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Walk a Little Faster (N.Y. opening: St. James Theatre, 1933 Jan 9; E.Y. Harburg-Duke songs)
      - "That's Life", 1 page (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - "Off Again, On Again" (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Typed lyrics with holograph corrections -- 2 pages
        Typed fragment -- 1 page
      - "April in Paris", 1 page (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Take a Chance (Paramount Pictures, 1933)
      - "It's Only a Paper Moon" (E.Y. Harburg-Billy Rose-Arlen) (Box 1, Folder 8)
        [Also used in The Great Magoo]
        Holograph lyrics for early version, rough draft in pencil -- 11 pages
        Typed lyrics with holograph corrections -- 1 page
    - Moonlight and Pretzels (Universal Pictures, 1933)
      - "Ah, But Is It Love?" (E.Y. Harburg-Gorney), 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 9)
        Manuscript of piano-vocal score with lyrics, handwritten in pencil [by Gorney or copyist?]
    - Ziegfeld Follies of 1934: Glorifying the American Girl (N.Y. opening: Winter Garden, 1934 Jan 4)
      - "I Like the Likes of You" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke) (Box 2, Folder 9)
        Revised typed lyrics with holograph corrections -- 1 page
        Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, 2 copies -- 1 page each
      - "Moon About Town" (E.Y. Harburg-Dana Suesse), 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - "To the Beat of My Heart" (E.Y. Harburg-Samuel Pokrass), 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 9)
        Holograph notes for lyrics, in ink
      - "What Is There to Say?" (E.Y. Harburg-Duke), 1 page (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Life Begins At 8:40 (N.Y. opening: Winter Garden, 1934 Sep 10; E.Y. Harburg-Ira Gershwin-Arlen songs)
      - Program (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - "You're a Builder Upper", 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - "C'est La Vie", 1 page (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - "What Can You Say in a Love Song?", 1 page (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - "Let's Take a Walk Around the Block", 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - "Things" (Box 2, Folder 9)
        Typed lyrics with holograph annotations -- 1 page
      - "All the Elks and Masons" (or "Join Up With Me"), 1 page (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - "I Couldn't Hold My Man", 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - "Rabelais", 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Broadway Gondolier (Warner Pictures, 1935)
      - Book by Sig Herzig, Hans Kraly, and E.Y. Harburg (Box 2, Folder 10)
        Typescript -- 34 pages
        Typescript, carbon copy (different version) -- 32 pages
    - Stage Struck (First National picture, 1936)
      - "In Your Own Quiet Way", 1 page each (Box 2, Folder 11)
        Typed lyrics with holograph corrections, 2 copies
      - "Four Fugitives from a Bolero Chain Gang" [song or patter], 4 pages each (Box 2, Folder 11)
        Typed script passage including lyrics, 2 copies
    - The Singing Kid (First National picture, 1936; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs)
      - "I Love to Sing-a" (Box 2, Folder 11)
        Typed script passage, including lyrics, patter, & chorus, with holograph annotations, 2 different copies -- 6 pages each
        Revised typed script with lyrics, patter, & chorus (changes made by Yacht Club Boys) -- 7 pages
      - "You're the Cure for What Ails Me", 1 page (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - "My, How This Country's Changed", 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 11)
        Typed lyrics with holograph annotations
    - Gold Diggers of 1937 (First National picture, 1937)
      - "Speaking of the Weather" (E.Y. Harburg-Arlen), 1 page (Box 2, Folder 11)
        Holograph lyrics in ink
    - Hooray for What! (N.Y. opening: Winter Garden, 1937 Dec 6; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs)
      - Early typed outline for story later developed for Hooray for What!, 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 12a)
      - Typed outlines of story by Crouse, Lindsey, & E.Y. Harburg (Box 2, Folder 12a)
        rough draft -- 14 pages
        final draft -- 14 pages
        Enclosure: holograph note -- 1 page
        Complete typescript with lyrics -- 73 pages
        The Playgoer Magazine: Forrest Theatre, 1937 Nov. 16
        Playbill: Winter Garden
      - Typed lyrics with holograph corrections (Box 2, Folder 12b)
        - "Hooray for What!", 2 slightly different versions, 1 page each (Box 2, Folder 12b)
        - "God's Country", 2 slightly different versions, 2 pages, 1 page (Box 2, Folder 12b)
        - "I've Gone Romantic on You", 1 page (Box 2, Folder 12b)
        - "Moanin' in the Mornin'", 2 slightly different versions, 2 pages, 1 page (Box 2, Folder 12b)
        - "Viva for Geneva", 1 page (Box 2, Folder 12b)
        - "On With the Dance" (or "Life's a Dance"), 2 versions, 1 page each (Box 2, Folder 12b)
        - "Napoleon's a Pastry", 1 page (Box 2, Folder 12b)
          [Song was used in N.Y. opening. Marginal note by E.Y. Harburg: "This song was dropped from Hooray for What & later rewritten for... Lena Horne with new tune."]
        - "Down with Love" (Box 2, Folder 12b)
          Version including patter -- 3 pages
          Slightly different version -- 2 pages
        - "The Night of the Embassy Ball", 1 page (Box 2, Folder 12b)
        - "In the Shade of the New Apple Tree", 2 slightly different versions, 1 page each (Box 2, Folder 12b)
          Typed & holograph lyrics with corrections
        - "Buds Won't Bud", 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 12b)
        - "I Click ze Heel and Kiss ze Hand" [not used in N.Y.] (Box 2, Folder 12b)
          1 complete -- 2 pages
          1 incomplete -- 1 page
      - Holograph notes & draft lyrics in pencil (Box 2, Folder 12b)
        "Hooray for What[!]" -- 3 pages
        "God's Country" -- 7 pages
        "Moanin' in the Mornin'" -- 6 pages
        "Viva for Geneva" -- 1 page
        "Down With Love" -- 5 pages
        "The Night of the Embassy Ball" -- 14 pages
        "In the Shade of the New Apple Tree" -- 4 pages
        "Buds Won't Bud" -- 5 pages
        "I Click ze Heel and Kiss ze Hand" [used in Boston] -- 7 pages
      - Holograph lists of titles, notes, song ideas, in pencil, 18 pages (Box 2, Folder 12b)
    - A Day at the Circus (MGM, 1939; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs)
      - "Lydia, the Tattooed Lady", 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - "Two Blind Loves", 1 page (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - The Wizard of Oz (MGM, 1939; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs)
      - First draft lyrics & notes, holograph, in pencil, 69 pages (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - "Over the Rainbow" (Box 2, Folder 14)
          Holograph description of song's history, in ink -- 1 page
          Original leadsheet by Harold Arlen, in pencil -- 1 page
          Typed lyrics with holograph corrections -- 3 pages
        - "Munchkin Musical Sequence", 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - "Ding-Dong! The Witch is Dead", 1 page (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - "We're Off to See the Wizard" (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - "If I Only Had a Brain" ("Heart," "Nerve"), 3 pages (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - "The Land of Oz", 1 page (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - "The Merry Old Land of Oz", 1 page (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - "If I Were King of the Forest", 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - Renovation Sequence: "At the Emerald City Beauty Shop", 1 page (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - "The Jitterbug" [cut from film], 3 pages (Box 2, Folder 14)
          Studio version of piano-vocal score with lyrics; holograph annotations in margin
      - Bound volume of published & studio piano-vocal scores with lyrics (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - "Over the Rainbow", 4 pages (Box 2, Folder 15)
          (Leo Feist, Inc., pub.)
        - "Munchkin Musical Sequence", 17 pages (Box 2, Folder 15)
          (studio manuscript)
        - "Ding-Dong! The Witch is Dead", 4 pages (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - "We're Off to See the Wizard", 3 pages (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - "If I Only Had a Brain" ("Heart," "Nerve"), 4 pages (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - Choral Sequence to "Gates of Emerald City", 2 pages (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - "The Merry Old Land of Oz", 4 pages (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - Renovation Sequence, 3 pages (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - "If I Were King of the Forest", 9 pages (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - "The Jitterbug", 5 pages (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Independent Songs, 1930s
      - "Isn't It Heavenly" (E.Y. Harburg-Joseph Meyers, 1933), 1 page (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - "Last Night When We Were Young" (E.Y. Harburg-Arlen, 1936), 1 page (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Selection of published piano-vocal scores with lyrics in leather bound volume, 1930-1941
      [not in chronological order]
      - The Wizard of Oz (1939; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs) (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - Souvenir album with color photographs, Leo Feist, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 17)
          "Over the Rainbow" -- 2 pages
          "Ding-Dong! The Witch is Dead" -- 4 pages
          "If I Only Had a Brain" ("Heart," "Nerve") -- 4 pages
          "The Merry Old Land of Oz" -- 4 pages
          "We're Off to See the Wizard" -- 3 pages
        - "Six Song Hits" edition, Leo Feist, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 17)
          "Over the Rainbow" -- 4 pages
        - Single piano-vocal scores, Leo Feist, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 17)
          "The Jitterbug" -- 5 pages
          "Sobre el arco iris" ["Over the Rainbow" in Spanish] (Leo Feist, Inc.) -- 2 pages
        - A Day At the Circus (1939; E.Y. Harburg-Arlen songs) (Box 3, Folder 17)